A Guide to the Manuscripts of James Branch Cabell 1918-1954
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Maunscripts of James Branch Cabell, 1918-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-b
Microfilm
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was microfilmed and the originals returned to the owner on February 16, 1959.
Scope and Content Information
Cabell here discusses social engagements; books he has read; travels with his wife; the state of American fiction; articles he has published in The Literary Review; and his favorable opinion of Alfred A. Knopf. He also discusses his and Hergesheimer's work, including the publication of The High Place and Beyond Life; reviews of Jurgen; Line of Love; Cords of Vanity; Figures of Earth; Chivalry; and The Happy End by Hergesheimer.
This collection is on microfilm (M-1530) and the originals were returned to Mr. Cabell.
Arrangement
The items are listed in the order on which they appear on the microfilm.
Contents List
- James Branch Cabell to Joseph Hergesheimer October 4, 1927, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 2, 1928, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 26, 1946, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer August 12, 1920, ALS, 2 p., w/envelope
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 9, 1927, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 23, 1925, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 9, 1931, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 14, 1931, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer January 10, 1942, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 6, 1924, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer December 8, 1929, TLS, 1 p. w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer April 13, 1951, TLS, 1 p., w/envelope.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 29, 1954, TLS, 1 p.
- Margaret and James Cabell to Dorothy and Joseph Hergesheimer June 18, 1950, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer January 10, 1950, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer April 11, 1931, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 10, 1930, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 30, 1929, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 10, 1927, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer September 22, 1926, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 12, 1926, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 28, 1925, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 25, 1924, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer January 26, 1924, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 20, 1923, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer September 20, 1923, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 27, 1918, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 8, 1918, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 12, 1918, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 29, 1918, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer January 6, 1919, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 7, 1919, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 14, 1919, TLS, 2 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 19, 1919, TLS, 2 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer September 27, 1919, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 11 & 13, 1919, TLS, 2 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 31, 1919, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 10, 1919, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer January 21, 1920, ALS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 7, 1920, TLS, w/auto. postsript., 1p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer June 22, 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 1, 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer September 22, 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 16, 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 20, 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer December 8, 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 17, 1921, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 5, 1921, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 4, 1921, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 2, 1921, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 4, 1921, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer December 26, 1921, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer January 3, 1922, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer October 31, 1922, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer November 22, 1922, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer February 19, 1923, TLS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer July 17, 1923, ALS, 1 p.
- J.B.C. to Joseph Hergesheimer May 4, 1929, TLS, 1 p.